Toronto, ON Canada. M1V 5N4 (226)-759-3597

# SMIT NIRMAL

nirmals@uwindsor.ca LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SMITNIRMAL GITHUB.COM/SMITNIRMAL3597

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Full-Stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in software development process. Strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming Languages, Data Structures and Algorithms. Understanding of SDLC to deliver quality and consistency in performance. True team player with well-developed analytical, problem-solving, interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills acquired through professional work experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Applied Computing**

January 2019 – August 2020

University of Windsor, Windsor, Ontario, Canada

August 2014 - May 2018

**Bachelor of Technology, Computer Engineering** Ganpat University, Mehsana, Gujarat, India

## SKILLS

- Languages Python, Java, C#, .NET Core, ASP.NET, JavaScript, Database MongoDB, Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL TypeScript, HTML, CSS
- Cloud Tools AWS, Microsoft Azure, Heroku
- Frameworks Angular, Node.js, React, Express.js, .NET, Entity Framework, Ionic, Flask
- Server, SQLite, Firebase
- Project/Code Management Tools Git, JIRA, Bitbucket, SDLC, Agile, SCRUM
- Others Nginx, jQuery, JSON, XML, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools, Docker, Kubernetes

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Cloud .NET Developer

**BDO Canada** 

March 2021 – Present

Technologies: C#, .Net Core, Angular, HTML, SCSS, TypeScript, SQL Server, Azure DevOps

- Working on multiple projects simultaneously
- · Delivering development activities on time and on budget per project plan with the highest level of quality while producing code that is secure, reliable, reusable and scalable
- Understand and help refine un-stated requirements & work with the Development Manager, Business Analyst, and Project Manager to define software requirements; and to assess feasibility of solution within time constraints
- Proactively identify areas for improvement, seek solutions and make recommendations
- Work with the project team to review problems, define and test solutions

### Programmer Analyst - Intern

**Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan** 

January 2020 - August 2020

Technologies: Angular, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, Apache ActiveMQ, Redis, Azure Data Studio

- Responsible for developing micro-services in Angular, ASP.NET, Spring Boot and Python, also containerized them using Docker and orchestrated using Kubernetes
- Assisted for back end development to create Web APIs using Flask, .NET; performed Unit and Integrated testing
- Leveraged knowledge of Notebooks to share code snippets using Azure Data Studio in Azure cloud lab
- Duties included meeting with business partners, scrum masters and QA to identify and groom new functionality, upgrade existing functionality and system design changes in Agile- Scrum environment

## **Software Developer (Part-time)**

Bidja Innovations Inc.

January 2019 - December 2019

Technologies: Angular, Node.is, Ionic, Apache Cordova, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, JSON, Bitbucket

- Day to day duty included developing mobile application which connects to CNC machine and fetches live JSON data using Rest API; updated and maintained the data in firebase database
- Designed User Interface using web technologies such as Angular, Bootstrap 4, Ionic framework, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Apache Cordova to add native-app functionalities by ensuring that application is Android/iOS compatible
- Collaborated remotely with multiple team members in order to meet deliverables on time using GitHub

## **Android Developer Intern**

VeerKrupa Infotechs Pvt Ltd

January 2018 - April 2018

Technologies: Java, XML, SQL, Git

- Gained knowledge of debugging, profiling and optimizing Android Apps for performance; Worked alongside other engineers to help architect, build and iterate on major components and new product features for Java Android App
- Developed and maintained database objects such as tables, views, user defined functions and procedures, cursor, triggers, SQL joints in SQL server to access the database

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Participated in various academic coding competitions and secured top ranks in many of them
- Helped out participants during the coding competition for queries related to technical problems, provided resources for an event
- Demonstrated various professional skills while working at Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan